<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/ei-prototype-v1-static/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/ei-prototype-v1-static/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-03-18T06:42:03+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ei-prototype-v1-static/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Elections and Tech</title><subtitle>A global resource on the role of technology in elections.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">IFES Announces Voluntary Election Integrity Guidelines for Technology Companies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ei-prototype-v1-static/update/2024/02/28/press-release-launch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IFES Announces Voluntary Election Integrity Guidelines for Technology Companies" /><published>2024-02-28T23:12:36+09:00</published><updated>2024-02-28T23:12:36+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ei-prototype-v1-static/update/2024/02/28/press-release-launch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ei-prototype-v1-static/update/2024/02/28/press-release-launch.html"><![CDATA[<p>DRAFT DRAFT DRAFT</p>

<p>SEOUL, KOREA — In a historic year for global elections, the International Foundation for Electoral Systems, in partnership with prominent election authorities and technology companies, released Voluntary Election Integrity Guidelines for Technology Companies. With more than 70 countries holding national-level elections this year, these guidelines provide a shared set of expectations and practices for companies and election authorities as they each work to advance election integrity in a rapidly deteriorating information environment. The guidelines were released at the Summit for Democracy hosted by the Republic of Korea in Seoul.</p>

<p>Emerging technologies, such as generative AI, are making it more difficult for election authorities to identify and address misinformation and disinformation tactics that mislead the public. Bad actors, including authoritarian governments, are wielding these tools to sway elections. While independent election authorities attempt to hold these bad actors accountable, they are increasingly under attack.
The lack of alignment and communication between election authorities and technology companies has stifled coordination to make technology work in support of electoral processes. These guidelines establish a practical path for meaningful engagement and support between election authorities and technology companies. They will establish clear policies and processes to share information around elections, providing voters with high-quality information. They will also improve communications channels between technology companies and election authorities and reduce barriers to supporting election integrity for smaller and newer companies who aim to be responsible actors around elections.</p>

<p>“The information space is the single gravest threat to electoral integrity and global democracy,” IFES CEO and President Tony Banbury said. “Election authorities are among the most important defenders of democracy. Their engagement with technology companies is a key step to safeguarding election integrity.”</p>

<p>As more regulatory approaches to technology companies come out of the European Union, many countries are at risk of being further deprioritized. These guidelines aim to engage companies more fully in the work of supporting election authorities in countries where democracy is under threat, ensuring resources reach countries most at risk.</p>

<p>[Quote from election official about importance of this being focused on countries more at risk]</p>

<p>[Quote from technology company representative]</p>

<p>These guidelines are [just a step forward, etc.] [Maybe language about Summit for Democracy here]</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[DRAFT DRAFT DRAFT]]></summary></entry></feed>